Congratulations on mastering
the extended Kalman Filter.
With this, you can solve a lot of
problems related to advanced driver
assistance systems and
self-driving cars.
&gt;&gt; Absolutely, if you look into
the code of a car and cruise control
system with automatic distance keeping,
you will find an Extended Kalman Filter.
&gt;&gt; There is also another
technique gaining more and
more attention in this field.
It is called
the Unscented Kalman Filter or UKF.
And you can achieve even
better results with it.
The UKF is an alternative technique
to deal norming your process models,
or nonlinear measurement models.
But instead of linearizing a nonlinear
function, the UKF uses so-called
sigma points to approximate
the probability distribution.
&gt;&gt; This has two advantages.
In many cases the sigma points
approximate the nonlinear transition
better than a linearization does.
Also it is not necessary to
calculate Jacobian matrix.
&gt;&gt; What are students are going
to learn in the lesson?
&gt;&gt; This lesson has three parts.
First I will introduce a more
sophisticated process model
that is able to estimate
the turn rate of a.
Then I will show you how
the Unscented Kalman Filter
deals with this nonlinear process model.
Finally, we will implement the filter
together step by step in C++, and
use it to solve a challenging
tracking scenario.
&gt;&gt; Let's get started and
see how the UCAP works.