You implemented the sigma
point generation in C++.
That's very good,
because it's great preparation for
the project at the end of this module.
Now you know how to represent
the uncertainty of the posterior state
estimation with sigma points.
And we can put the sigma points
into the process function.
But wait a second.
The process function also considers
the process noise vector, mu k.
And this also has a non-linear effect.
Fortunately, the UKF
provides a super-easy way
to handle non-linear
process noise effects.
And this is what I want to
show you in this video.
Let's look into this
process noise again.
This is the complete process model.
Considering the process noise vector,
looking at this,
some of you might think, wait a second.
Didn't we say this type of vector
is the process vector nu K?
Yes, you are absolutely right.
In the last lesson about the Kalman
filter, this was what we called nu K.
And that made a big difference because
you had to calculate this big process
noise covariance matrix Q.
The thing is if look into literature and
you find this process noise vector,
nu K, you really have to be
careful of what the authors mean.
Sometimes they mean this vector.
Each row of this vector tells
the influence of the process
noise on a specific state between K and
K plus 1.
So it has the same dimension as the
state vector, and it depends on delta t.
Mostly this is the case when you read
about the standard linear Kalman filter,
but sometimes the authors
mean this vector.
This is something much simpler,
because this vector just lists the
individual independent noise processes.
This vector doesn't say anything about
the effect of these noise processes on
the state vector, and
it does not depend on delta t.
Usually this is what authors mean
when they write about the unscented
Kalman filter.
This issue confuses me a lot when I
started getting into Kalman filters.
So in this lesson about
the UKF when I mention nu K,
I'm always talking about
this process noise vector.
And this is a good thing
because the covariance matrix Q
of this process noise is
much simpler in this case.
To write down this matrix, you just need
to know the stochastic properties of
these noise processes,
which we already defined.
Then Q is given by this matrix.
This matrix contains the variances
of the noise processes.
The covariances here are zero because
the longitudinal acceleration noise and
the yaw acceleration noise
are considered independent.
Now we clarified what this
process noise vector is and
what its covariance matrix Q looks like.
What I want to show you now is how
you can represent the uncertainty of
the covariance matrix
Q with sigma points.
The solution is called augmentation.
This is an overview on how we generated
signal points without considering Q.
What we will do now is
build the augmented state,
where we add the noise
vector to the state vector.
I call this state Xa.
The augmented state
dimension in our case is 7.
This also means we need
15 sigma points now.
The additional four sigma
points will be representing
the uncertainty caused
by the process noise.
We also build the augmented
covariance matrix Pa.
This matrix has 7 rows and 7 columns.
You just add the matrix Q
as a lower right block, and
fill up the remaining fields with a 0.
Finally, the way to generate
the 15 sigma points
is exactly the same as before.
Just use the augmented
elements as input.
In the next quiz, you will adapt
your sigma point generation function
to the augmented state.