Congrats, you have made it
almost through the UKF.
This is the last step you need to learn,
and then you will be ready to
implement your own UKF and
fuse data from different sensors.
This is a very powerful and
useful ability.
So let's see how the final step works
and how you can update your state and
your covariance matrix
with the measurement.
What we have is this, the predicted
state mean and covariance and
the predicated measurement mean and
covariance.
But there's one more thing that we need,
and
this is the actual measurement zk+1
that we receive for the time step k+1.
This is actually the first
time we really need to
know the measurement values.
What we needed right from the beginning
was the time of the measurement, so
we could predict to the correct time.
And later, the sensor type so we could
use the correct measurement model
in the measurement prediction step.
But this is the first time where we
look into the measurement values.
The update calculation closes
the processing chain and
produces the updated state mean and
the updated state covariance matrix.
These equations are exactly the same
as for the standard Kalman filter.
The only difference here is how
you calculate the Kalman gain K.
Here you need the cross-correlation
matrix between the predicted sigma
points in the state space and
the predicted sigma points
in the measurement space.
And that's it.
With this, you're done processing
the measurement at time step k+1, and
you're ready to handle the next
measurement at time step k+2.