Welcome to the last coding
quiz before the project.
We want to calculate this time
is the UpdatedState X and
the UpdatedCovariance matrix P.
We need a lot of
pre-calculated data this time.
These are the predicted sigma
points in the state space.
This is the predicted state mean and
the state prediction covariance.
You can use this variable x again, and
override it later with
the updated state.
The same is true for
the variable p, override this one
with the updated covariance matrix.
Here we have the predicted sigma
points in the measurement space.
This is the predicted
measurement mean and
this is the covariance of
the measurement prediction.
And of course, you need some values for
the actual measurement z.
Here you can store your
intermediate results for
the cross correlation matrix t.
Again, make sure to use the variable
x and the variable P to store your
updated state and
your updated covariance matrix.
All right,
good luck with this final coding quiz.