Now, let's take a look at how
the assumption of a circular motion
leads to a process model.
So in this example,
at time k, the car's here.
The goal of the process model f is to
predict where the car is at time k + 1.
Written as an equation,
it looks like this.
The process model f predicts
the state at time step k + 1.
Given the state at time step k and
a noise vector new k,
this is the function we want to find.
What we want to do now is
derive this process model.
I will show you a very general and,
therefore, powerful approach.
You will be able to use this approach
to derive process models for
many, many real world problems.
We cannot directly write down the
process model simply by looking at this
figure.
But we can say something about
the change rate of the state x,
called x dot.
From the geometric relations,
we can directly derive how the change
rate x dot depends on the state x.
This is a differential equation.
What I would like you to do now is
derive this differential equation.
The goal is to express each of
the five-time relatives of the state,
independency of any of
the state elements.
I'll show you an example, Px dot is
the same as the velocity in x direction.
Unfortunately, the velocity
in x direction
is not part of the state vector,
otherwise, I would be finished already.
But the speed V and the origin of psi
are both elements of the state vector.
And if I look at this triangle,
I can identify that Vx
= cosine psi times V.
Now, go ahead and
pick the correct terms for
the four remaining change
rates of the state.