So, you already solved the last
three rows, that's great.
For the first two rows,
we actually have to solve the integral.
There is no way around this time.
First, let's insert the assumption
that the velocity v is a constant.
So we can move the velocity at time
K as a constant before the integral.
Also, we can explicitly express sin
as a function of T using again,
the assumption of a constant yar rate.
After the video,
take a moment to look at this term and
try to figure out what's going on here?
For the first two rows we now
have an explicit function of t.
All other variables are constants.
So now it is possible to
solve these integrals.
You can look up the solution of
these integrals in a text book or
you can solve them with an online tool.
You will find a link below the video.
Consider this a bonus question for
those who are really good
in solving Integrals.
I don't really expect you to
solve this Integral on the fly.
Unless of course you think you can.