Now we have the solution
of the integral.
It is a function that brings
the state from time step k,
to time step k + 1, awesome.
There's only one problem
with our solution and
that is the division by 0
when the yaw rate is in.
And this is an important
case because it means
the weakness driving on a straight road,
which happens quite often.
There are two ways to derive
the solution for this special case.
You can put the yaw rate to 0
right from the beginning and
solve the integral again,
for this special case.
But remember, when the yaw rate is 0,
it means the weaker drives
in a straight line.
In this case,
you can also directly see the solution
by looking at the triangle again.
In the next quiz, try to identify
the correct process model for
the special case when the yaw rate is 0.