What we have introduced so far was the
deterministic part of the process model.
But of course, we also need to consider
the stochastic part of the process model
and that has something to do
with the process noise new k.
We will describe the uncertainty of
the process model with a two-dimensional
noise vector new k, consisting of two
independent scalar noise processes.
The first noise process is the
longitudinal acceleration noise new a.
It influences the longitudinal
speed of the vehicle and
it randomly changes its
value at every time step k.
The longitudinal acceleration
is a normally distributed white
noise with zero mean and
the variance sigma a squared.
The other noise process is the yaw
acceleration new site dot dot.
It is also a normal distributed
white noise with zero mean and
it has the variance sigma
yaw dot dot squared.
And what I want to discuss with you
next is how the noise vector new
k influences our process model.